// ~ Kathrin

export const countriesData = {
  Germany: {
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the capital of Germany?",
        options: ["Munich", "Hamburg", "Berlin", "Frankfurt"],
        correctAnswer: "Berlin",
        explanation:
          "Berlin has been the capital of Germany since 1990 after the reunification of East and West Germany."
      },
      {
        question: "What year did Germany reunify?",
        options: ["1989", "1990", "1991", "1992"],
        correctAnswer: "1990",
        explanation:
          "Germany reunified in 1990, following the fall of the Berlin Wall in 1989."
      },
      {
        question: "Which famous wall divided East and West Berlin?",
        options: [
          "Brandenburg Wall",
          "Berlin Wall",
          "Iron Curtain",
          "Reichstag Wall"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Berlin Wall",
        explanation: "The Berlin Wall divided the city from 1961 to 1989."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the currency used in Germany?",
        options: ["Deutschmark", "Franc", "Euro", "Pound"],
        correctAnswer: "Euro",
        explanation:
          "Germany adopted the Euro in 2002, replacing the Deutschmark."
      },
      {
        question: "Who was Germany's leader during World War II?",
        options: [
          "Otto von Bismarck",
          "Adolf Hitler",
          "Kaiser Wilhelm II",
          "Angela Merkel"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Adolf Hitler",
        explanation:
          "Adolf Hitler led Nazi Germany from 1933 until his death in 1945."
      },
      {
        question: "Which German city is known for its annual Oktoberfest?",
        options: ["Frankfurt", "Stuttgart", "Munich", "Berlin"],
        correctAnswer: "Munich",
        explanation:
          "Oktoberfest is celebrated annually in Munich and is the world's largest beer festival."
      },
      {
        question: "Which German composer wrote the famous 'Fur Elise'?",
        options: ["Bach", "Mozart", "Beethoven", "Wagner"],
        correctAnswer: "Beethoven",
        explanation: "'Für Elise' was composed by Ludwig van Beethoven in 1810."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which German car brand has the slogan 'Vorsprung durch Technik'?",
        options: ["BMW", "Volkswagen", "Audi", "Mercedes-Benz"],
        correctAnswer: "Audi",
        explanation: "Audi's slogan means 'Advancement through Technology.'"
      },
      {
        question: "Germany is the world's largest producer of which beverage?",
        options: ["Wine", "Beer", "Whiskey", "Vodka"],
        correctAnswer: "Beer",
        explanation:
          "Germany is known worldwide for its beer production, especially its brewing traditions."
      },
      {
        question: "Which river is the longest in Germany?",
        options: ["Danube", "Elbe", "Rhine", "Main"],
        correctAnswer: "Rhine",
        explanation:
          "The Rhine is the longest river in Germany, stretching over 1,230 kilometers."
      }
    ]
  },
  Germany_2nd_Reich: {
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Who was the first Kaiser (Emperor) of the German Empire (2nd Reich)?",
        options: [
          "Otto von Bismarck",
          "Wilhelm I",
          "Frederick III",
          "Wilhelm II"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Wilhelm I",
        explanation:
          "Wilhelm I became the first emperor of a unified Germany in 1871."
      },
      {
        question: "In which year was the German Empire proclaimed?",
        options: ["1815", "1848", "1871", "1914"],
        correctAnswer: "1871",
        explanation:
          "The German Empire was proclaimed in the Hall of Mirrors in Versailles in 1871 after the Franco-Prussian War."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which war led to the unification of the German states under Prussian leadership?",
        options: [
          "Franco-Prussian War",
          "Austro-Prussian War",
          "Napoleonic Wars",
          "World War I"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Franco-Prussian War",
        explanation:
          "The Franco-Prussian War (1870-1871) directly led to the unification of Germany."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who was the leading political figure behind the creation of the German Empire?",
        options: [
          "Wilhelm II",
          "Otto von Bismarck",
          "Adolf Hitler",
          "Paul von Hindenburg"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Otto von Bismarck",
        explanation:
          "Bismarck, the 'Iron Chancellor,' masterminded the unification of Germany."
      },
      {
        question: "What was the capital of the German Empire?",
        options: ["Munich", "Frankfurt", "Berlin", "Hamburg"],
        correctAnswer: "Berlin",
        explanation:
          "Berlin was the capital of the German Empire from 1871 until its collapse in 1918."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which kingdom was the dominant force within the German Empire?",
        options: ["Bavaria", "Prussia", "Saxony", "Baden"],
        correctAnswer: "Prussia",
        explanation:
          "Prussia was the largest and most powerful state in the German Empire."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which German Chancellor is associated with the policy of 'Realpolitik'?",
        options: [
          "Wilhelm I",
          "Otto von Bismarck",
          "Friedrich Ebert",
          "Helmut Kohl"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Otto von Bismarck",
        explanation:
          "Bismarck used Realpolitik to achieve German unification and consolidate power."
      },
      {
        question: "What event marked the end of the German Empire?",
        options: [
          "The defeat in World War I",
          "The German Revolution",
          "The Treaty of Versailles",
          "The abdication of Kaiser Wilhelm II"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "The abdication of Kaiser Wilhelm II",
        explanation:
          "The abdication of Wilhelm II in 1918 marked the end of the German Empire."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which industrial region was vital to the German Empire's economy?",
        options: ["Ruhr Valley", "Black Forest", "Bavaria", "Thuringia"],
        correctAnswer: "Ruhr Valley",
        explanation:
          "The Ruhr Valley was Germany’s most important industrial area, producing coal and steel."
      },
      {
        question: "What was the German Empire's colonial empire called?",
        options: [
          "Third Reich",
          "German New Guinea",
          "German East Africa",
          "German Empire"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "German Empire",
        explanation:
          "Germany's colonial empire, primarily in Africa and the Pacific, was under the German Empire."
      }
    ]
  },
  Romania: {
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Who was the famous Romanian ruler known for defending against the Ottoman Empire?",
        options: [
          "Michael the Brave",
          "Vlad the Impaler",
          "Stephen the Great",
          "Alexandru Ioan Cuza"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Vlad the Impaler",
        explanation:
          "Vlad the Impaler, also known as Dracula, was known for his brutal methods of defending Wallachia."
      },
      {
        question: "What year did Romania become a unified country?",
        options: ["1829", "1859", "1918", "1920"],
        correctAnswer: "1859",
        explanation:
          "Romania unified in 1859 through the merging of Moldavia and Wallachia."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which Romanian region was once part of the Austro-Hungarian Empire?",
        options: ["Wallachia", "Transylvania", "Moldavia", "Banat"],
        correctAnswer: "Transylvania",
        explanation:
          "Transylvania was part of the Austro-Hungarian Empire until the Treaty of Trianon in 1920."
      },
      {
        question: "Which major river flows through Romania?",
        options: ["Danube", "Rhine", "Volga", "Seine"],
        correctAnswer: "Danube",
        explanation:
          "The Danube is the second-longest river in Europe, flowing through several countries, including Romania."
      },
      {
        question: "When did Romania join the European Union?",
        options: ["1995", "2000", "2007", "2010"],
        correctAnswer: "2007",
        explanation:
          "Romania joined the European Union in 2007, alongside Bulgaria."
      },
      {
        question: "Which dictator ruled Romania from 1965 to 1989?",
        options: [
          "Ion Antonescu",
          "Nicolae Ceaușescu",
          "Emil Constantinescu",
          "Traian Băsescu"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Nicolae Ceaușescu",
        explanation:
          "Nicolae Ceaușescu ruled Romania until his overthrow and execution in 1989."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the capital city of Romania?",
        options: ["Cluj-Napoca", "Timișoara", "Iași", "Bucharest"],
        correctAnswer: "Bucharest",
        explanation: "Bucharest is Romania’s largest city and capital."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the famous legend associated with Romania?",
        options: [
          "Count Dracula",
          "The Hunchback of Notre Dame",
          "Frankenstein",
          "The Phantom of the Opera"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Count Dracula",
        explanation:
          "Dracula, based on Vlad the Impaler, is a famous legend associated with Transylvania, Romania."
      },
      {
        question: "Which sea borders Romania?",
        options: [
          "Black Sea",
          "Mediterranean Sea",
          "Baltic Sea",
          "Adriatic Sea"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Black Sea",
        explanation: "Romania has a coastline along the Black Sea."
      },
      {
        question: "What is Romania's official language?",
        options: ["Hungarian", "Romanian", "German", "Slovak"],
        correctAnswer: "Romanian",
        explanation:
          "Romanian is the official language, and it's part of the Romance language family."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which famous Romanian gymnast won six gold medals at the 1976 Olympics?",
        options: [
          "Nadia Comăneci",
          "Simona Halep",
          "Elena Gheorghe",
          "Gina Pistol"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Nadia Comăneci",
        explanation:
          "Nadia Comăneci is famous for scoring the first perfect 10 in Olympic gymnastics history."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the largest castle in Romania, often associated with Dracula?",
        options: [
          "Peleș Castle",
          "Bran Castle",
          "Corvin Castle",
          "Hunyad Castle"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Bran Castle",
        explanation:
          "Bran Castle is often referred to as 'Dracula's Castle' due to its association with the Dracula legend."
      },
      {
        question: "Which mountain range runs through Romania?",
        options: [
          "Carpathian Mountains",
          "Apuseni Mountains",
          "Alps",
          "Balkan Mountains"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Carpathian Mountains",
        explanation:
          "The Carpathian Mountains are a major mountain range that runs through Romania."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What traditional Romanian dish is made with fermented cabbage?",
        options: ["Mămăligă", "Sarmale", "Ciorbă", "Mici"],
        correctAnswer: "Sarmale",
        explanation:
          "Sarmale are grape or cabbage rolls filled with minced meat and rice."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the name of the famous Romanian festival that celebrates traditional crafts and folk culture?",
        options: [
          "Sărbătoarea Mărțișorului",
          "Festivalul Enescu",
          "Târgul de Crăciun",
          "Folk You Festival"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Sărbătoarea Mărțișorului",
        explanation:
          "Sărbătoarea Mărțișorului marks the arrival of spring and features traditional crafts and folklore."
      }
    ]
  },
  Poland: {
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the capital of Poland?",
        options: ["Warsaw", "Kraków", "Gdańsk", "Wrocław"],
        correctAnswer: "Warsaw",
        explanation: "Warsaw is the capital and largest city of Poland."
      },
      {
        question: "Which event is commemorated on the 1st of August in Poland?",
        options: [
          "Independence Day",
          "Warsaw Uprising",
          "Constitution Day",
          "Defenders' Day"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Warsaw Uprising",
        explanation:
          "The Warsaw Uprising began on August 1, 1944, during World War II."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the traditional Polish dish made of fermented rye flour?",
        options: ["Bigos", "Kielbasa", "Żurek", "Pierogi"],
        correctAnswer: "Żurek",
        explanation: "Żurek is a sour rye soup often served with sausage."
      },
      {
        question: "Which famous scientist was born in Poland?",
        options: [
          "Isaac Newton",
          "Albert Einstein",
          "Marie Curie",
          "Galileo Galilei"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Marie Curie",
        explanation:
          "Marie Curie was born in Warsaw and is known for her research on radioactivity."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the currency used in Poland?",
        options: ["Zloty", "Euro", "Franc", "Koruna"],
        correctAnswer: "Zloty",
        explanation:
          "The official currency of Poland is the Polish Zloty (PLN)."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the name of Poland's famous salt mine, a UNESCO World Heritage site?",
        options: ["Wieliczka", "Auschwitz", "Malbork", "Bialowieza"],
        correctAnswer: "Wieliczka",
        explanation:
          "The Wieliczka Salt Mine is renowned for its underground chapels and sculptures."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which Polish city is known for its historic Old Town and was rebuilt after WWII?",
        options: ["Gdańsk", "Kraków", "Warsaw", "Poznań"],
        correctAnswer: "Warsaw",
        explanation:
          "Warsaw's Old Town was meticulously reconstructed after being destroyed during the war."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the name of the Polish mountain range that is a popular tourist destination?",
        options: ["Carpathians", "Alps", "Tatras", "Pyrenees"],
        correctAnswer: "Tatras",
        explanation:
          "The Tatras are a part of the Carpathian mountain range, known for hiking and skiing."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which historical figure is associated with the Solidarity movement in Poland?",
        options: [
          "Lech Wałęsa",
          "Tadeusz Kościuszko",
          "Jerzy Grotowski",
          "Władysław Sikorski"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Lech Wałęsa",
        explanation:
          "Lech Wałęsa was a leader of the Solidarity movement and served as President of Poland."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the national symbol of Poland?",
        options: ["Eagle", "Lion", "Bear", "Dragon"],
        correctAnswer: "Eagle",
        explanation:
          "The White Eagle is the national emblem of Poland, symbolizing strength and freedom."
      }
    ]
  },
  Spain: {
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the capital of Spain?",
        options: ["Madrid", "Barcelona", "Seville", "Valencia"],
        correctAnswer: "Madrid",
        explanation: "Madrid is the capital and largest city of Spain."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which famous Spanish artist is known for his work during the Cubist movement?",
        options: [
          "Salvador Dalí",
          "Pablo Picasso",
          "Francisco Goya",
          "Diego Velázquez"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Pablo Picasso",
        explanation:
          "Pablo Picasso is one of the most influential artists of the 20th century and co-founder of Cubism."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the traditional Spanish dish made of rice, saffron, and various meats or seafood?",
        options: ["Tortilla", "Paella", "Gazpacho", "Churros"],
        correctAnswer: "Paella",
        explanation:
          "Paella originated in Valencia and is one of Spain's most famous dishes."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which festival is held annually in Pamplona, known for its running of the bulls?",
        options: ["La Tomatina", "San Fermín", "Fallas", "Semana Santa"],
        correctAnswer: "San Fermín",
        explanation:
          "The San Fermín festival includes the famous running of the bulls and takes place in July."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the currency used in Spain?",
        options: ["Peseta", "Euro", "Dollar", "Franc"],
        correctAnswer: "Euro",
        explanation:
          "Spain adopted the Euro in 2002, replacing the Spanish Peseta."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which architectural landmark in Barcelona was designed by Antoni Gaudí?",
        options: ["Sagrada Família", "Park Güell", "Alhambra", "Burj Khalifa"],
        correctAnswer: "Sagrada Família",
        explanation:
          "The Sagrada Família is a famous basilica designed by Gaudí and is still under construction."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the Spanish term for a midday meal, which is typically the largest meal of the day?",
        options: ["Desayuno", "Almuerzo", "Cena", "Tapas"],
        correctAnswer: "Almuerzo",
        explanation:
          "Almuerzo refers to the main meal of the day in Spain, usually eaten in the afternoon."
      },
      {
        question: "Which Spanish region is famous for its flamenco dance?",
        options: ["Catalonia", "Andalusia", "Galicia", "Basque Country"],
        correctAnswer: "Andalusia",
        explanation:
          "Flamenco originated in Andalusia and is a significant part of Spanish culture."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the Spanish national football team?",
        options: ["La Roja", "Los Blancos", "La Furia Roja", "Los Colchoneros"],
        correctAnswer: "La Roja",
        explanation:
          "La Roja is the nickname for the Spanish national football team, referring to their red uniforms."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which Spanish island is known for its beautiful beaches and nightlife?",
        options: ["Ibiza", "Tenerife", "Mallorca", "Gran Canaria"],
        correctAnswer: "Ibiza",
        explanation:
          "Ibiza is famous for its vibrant nightlife and stunning beaches."
      }
    ]
  },
  Portugal: {
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the capital of Portugal?",
        options: ["Lisbon", "Porto", "Coimbra", "Braga"],
        correctAnswer: "Lisbon",
        explanation: "Lisbon is the capital and largest city of Portugal."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which famous Portuguese explorer is known for discovering the sea route to India?",
        options: [
          "Ferdinand Magellan",
          "Vasco da Gama",
          "Henry the Navigator",
          "Christopher Columbus"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Vasco da Gama",
        explanation:
          "Vasco da Gama was the first to sail directly from Europe to India."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the traditional Portuguese dish made with salt cod?",
        options: ["Francesinha", "Bacalhau", "Pastel de nata", "Caldo verde"],
        correctAnswer: "Bacalhau",
        explanation:
          "Bacalhau is a staple in Portuguese cuisine, often prepared in various dishes."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the currency used in Portugal?",
        options: ["Escudo", "Euro", "Pound", "Dollar"],
        correctAnswer: "Euro",
        explanation:
          "Portugal adopted the Euro in 2002, replacing the Portuguese Escudo."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which region of Portugal is famous for its wine production, particularly Port wine?",
        options: ["Alentejo", "Dão", "Douro Valley", "Minho"],
        correctAnswer: "Douro Valley",
        explanation:
          "The Douro Valley is known for producing Port wine and has been designated a UNESCO World Heritage site."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the name of the famous Portuguese pastry filled with custard?",
        options: [
          "Bola de Berlim",
          "Pastel de nata",
          "Tarte Tatin",
          "Bolo Rei"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Pastel de nata",
        explanation:
          "Pastel de nata is a popular custard tart that originated in Lisbon."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the traditional folk music genre from Portugal, known for its expressive singing?",
        options: ["Fado", "Flamenco", "Samba", "Bossa Nova"],
        correctAnswer: "Fado",
        explanation:
          "Fado is a genre of Portuguese music characterized by its melancholic themes."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which Portuguese city is known for its historic architecture and is a UNESCO World Heritage site?",
        options: ["Lisbon", "Porto", "Sintra", "Évora"],
        correctAnswer: "Sintra",
        explanation:
          "Sintra is famous for its romantic 19th-century architecture and stunning palaces."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of Portugal's largest river?",
        options: ["Douro", "Tejo", "Guadiana", "Mondego"],
        correctAnswer: "Tejo",
        explanation:
          "The Tejo River is the longest river in Portugal, flowing through Lisbon before emptying into the Atlantic Ocean."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which island group is an autonomous region of Portugal known for its volcanic landscapes?",
        options: ["Azores", "Madeira", "Baleares", "Canarias"],
        correctAnswer: "Azores",
        explanation:
          "The Azores are a group of islands in the North Atlantic Ocean, known for their stunning nature and biodiversity."
      }
    ]
  },
  Moldova: {
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the capital of Moldova?",
        options: ["Chișinău", "Bălți", "Tighina", "Orhei"],
        correctAnswer: "Chișinău",
        explanation: "Chișinău is the capital and largest city of Moldova."
      },
      {
        question: "Which river forms the eastern border of Moldova?",
        options: ["Dniester", "Prut", "Danube", "Nistru"],
        correctAnswer: "Dniester",
        explanation:
          "The Dniester River forms part of the eastern border of Moldova."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the traditional Moldovan dish made from cornmeal?",
        options: ["Mămăligă", "Sarmale", "Plăcintă", "Ciorbă"],
        correctAnswer: "Mămăligă",
        explanation:
          "Mămăligă is a popular dish in Moldova, made from cornmeal and often served with cheese or sour cream."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which wine region in Moldova is famous for its underground wine cellars?",
        options: ["Cricova", "Codru", "Purcari", "Valea Calugărească"],
        correctAnswer: "Cricova",
        explanation:
          "Cricova is known for its vast underground wine cellars and extensive wine production."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the official language of Moldova?",
        options: ["Romanian", "Russian", "Ukrainian", "Moldovan"],
        correctAnswer: "Romanian",
        explanation:
          "The official language of Moldova is Romanian, often referred to as Moldovan."
      },
      {
        question: "Which UNESCO World Heritage site is located in Moldova?",
        options: [
          "Old Orhei",
          "Saharna Monastery",
          "Codru Natural Reserve",
          "Cricova Wine Cellars"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Old Orhei",
        explanation:
          "Old Orhei is an archaeological complex and UNESCO World Heritage site in Moldova."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the currency used in Moldova?",
        options: ["Leu", "Euro", "Dollar", "Ruble"],
        correctAnswer: "Leu",
        explanation:
          "The official currency of Moldova is the Moldovan Leu (MDL)."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which national celebration takes place on March 1st in Moldova?",
        options: [
          "Mărțișor",
          "Independence Day",
          "Language Day",
          "Victory Day"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Mărțișor",
        explanation:
          "Mărțișor is a traditional spring celebration in Moldova, symbolizing the arrival of spring."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which region is known for its diverse cultural heritage and is home to many ethnic minorities?",
        options: ["Gagauzia", "Transnistria", "Bessarabia", "Moldova-Nouă"],
        correctAnswer: "Gagauzia",
        explanation:
          "Gagauzia is an autonomous territorial unit in Moldova known for its unique culture and ethnic diversity."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the main religion practiced in Moldova?",
        options: [
          "Orthodox Christianity",
          "Catholicism",
          "Protestantism",
          "Islam"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Orthodox Christianity",
        explanation:
          "Orthodox Christianity is the predominant religion in Moldova, with the majority of the population adhering to this faith."
      }
    ]
  },
  Italy: {
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the capital of Italy?",
        options: ["Rome", "Milan", "Florence", "Venice"],
        correctAnswer: "Rome",
        explanation:
          "Rome is the capital and largest city of Italy, known for its rich history."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which famous Italian artist painted the Sistine Chapel ceiling?",
        options: ["Leonardo da Vinci", "Michelangelo", "Raphael", "Caravaggio"],
        correctAnswer: "Michelangelo",
        explanation:
          "Michelangelo painted the iconic Sistine Chapel ceiling, which features scenes from the Bible."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the name of the famous Italian dish made with thinly sliced raw meat or fish?",
        options: ["Carpaccio", "Bruschetta", "Frittata", "Risotto"],
        correctAnswer: "Carpaccio",
        explanation:
          "Carpaccio is a dish consisting of thinly sliced raw meat or fish, typically served as an appetizer."
      },
      {
        question: "Which Italian city is known as the 'City of Canals'?",
        options: ["Florence", "Venice", "Naples", "Bologna"],
        correctAnswer: "Venice",
        explanation:
          "Venice is famous for its canals, making it a unique and picturesque city."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the currency used in Italy?",
        options: ["Lira", "Euro", "Dollar", "Pound"],
        correctAnswer: "Euro",
        explanation:
          "Italy adopted the Euro as its official currency in 2002, replacing the Italian Lira."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which landmark is considered a symbol of Italy and is located in Pisa?",
        options: ["Colosseum", "Leaning Tower", "Trevi Fountain", "Vatican"],
        correctAnswer: "Leaning Tower",
        explanation:
          "The Leaning Tower of Pisa is famous for its unintended tilt and is a UNESCO World Heritage site."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the traditional Italian coffee drink made with espresso and steamed milk?",
        options: ["Cappuccino", "Macchiato", "Latte", "Espresso"],
        correctAnswer: "Cappuccino",
        explanation:
          "A cappuccino is made with equal parts of espresso, steamed milk, and milk foam."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which ancient civilization is known for building the Colosseum?",
        options: ["Greeks", "Romans", "Etruscans", "Byzantines"],
        correctAnswer: "Romans",
        explanation:
          "The Romans built the Colosseum, an iconic amphitheater located in Rome."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the name of the famous Italian fashion city known for its high-end designers?",
        options: ["Milan", "Florence", "Venice", "Rome"],
        correctAnswer: "Milan",
        explanation:
          "Milan is considered one of the fashion capitals of the world."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the Italian term for a pasta dish that is typically served with a sauce and cheese?",
        options: ["Ragu", "Pasta al Forno", "Lasagna", "Spaghetti"],
        correctAnswer: "Spaghetti",
        explanation:
          "Spaghetti is a type of pasta that is often served with various sauces, including marinara."
      }
    ]
  },
  Greece: {
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the capital of Greece?",
        options: ["Athens", "Thessaloniki", "Heraklion", "Patras"],
        correctAnswer: "Athens",
        explanation:
          "Athens is the capital and largest city of Greece, known for its ancient history."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which ancient structure is a symbol of Greece and located on the Acropolis?",
        options: ["Parthenon", "Colosseum", "Eiffel Tower", "Louvre Museum"],
        correctAnswer: "Parthenon",
        explanation:
          "The Parthenon is an ancient temple dedicated to the goddess Athena, located on the Acropolis."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the traditional Greek dish made of minced meat wrapped in grape leaves?",
        options: ["Moussaka", "Dolmades", "Souvlaki", "Spanakopita"],
        correctAnswer: "Dolmades",
        explanation:
          "Dolmades are grape leaves stuffed with rice, herbs, and minced meat."
      },
      {
        question: "Which sea is located to the south of Greece?",
        options: [
          "Mediterranean Sea",
          "Aegean Sea",
          "Ionian Sea",
          "Adriatic Sea"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Mediterranean Sea",
        explanation: "Greece is bordered by the Mediterranean Sea to the south."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the currency used in Greece?",
        options: ["Drachma", "Euro", "Dollar", "Pound"],
        correctAnswer: "Euro",
        explanation:
          "Greece adopted the Euro as its official currency in 2002, replacing the Drachma."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which Greek island is famous for its blue domed churches and whitewashed buildings?",
        options: ["Crete", "Rhodes", "Santorini", "Corfu"],
        correctAnswer: "Santorini",
        explanation:
          "Santorini is known for its stunning architecture and breathtaking views."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the name of the ancient Greek festival held in honor of the god Dionysus?",
        options: [
          "Olympics",
          "Panathenaic Festival",
          "Dionysia",
          "Pythian Games"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Dionysia",
        explanation:
          "The Dionysia was an important festival in ancient Athens featuring dramatic performances."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the traditional Greek yogurt dish often served with honey and nuts?",
        options: ["Tzatziki", "Baklava", "Feta", "Greek Yogurt"],
        correctAnswer: "Greek Yogurt",
        explanation:
          "Greek yogurt is a thick, creamy yogurt often served with honey and nuts."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the name of the famous ancient Greek philosopher who taught Alexander the Great?",
        options: ["Plato", "Socrates", "Aristotle", "Epicurus"],
        correctAnswer: "Aristotle",
        explanation:
          "Aristotle was a Greek philosopher who taught Alexander the Great and made significant contributions to various fields of knowledge."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which Greek dish consists of layers of eggplant, minced meat, and béchamel sauce?",
        options: ["Moussaka", "Spanakopita", "Baklava", "Souvlaki"],
        correctAnswer: "Moussaka",
        explanation:
          "Moussaka is a traditional Greek dish made with layers of eggplant, meat, and béchamel sauce."
      }
    ]
  },
  Croatia: {
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the capital of Croatia?",
        options: ["Zagreb", "Split", "Dubrovnik", "Rijeka"],
        correctAnswer: "Zagreb",
        explanation:
          "Zagreb is the capital and largest city of Croatia, located in the northwestern part of the country."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which famous national park in Croatia is known for its cascading lakes?",
        options: ["Plitvice Lakes", "Krka", "Paklenica", "Brijuni"],
        correctAnswer: "Plitvice Lakes",
        explanation:
          "Plitvice Lakes National Park is famous for its stunning lakes and waterfalls, a UNESCO World Heritage site."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the currency used in Croatia?",
        options: ["Euro", "Kuna", "Dollar", "Pound"],
        correctAnswer: "Kuna",
        explanation:
          "The official currency of Croatia is the Croatian Kuna (HRK)."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which city is known for its well-preserved medieval architecture and the historic Diocletian's Palace?",
        options: ["Dubrovnik", "Zagreb", "Split", "Pula"],
        correctAnswer: "Split",
        explanation:
          "Split is home to Diocletian's Palace, a UNESCO World Heritage site and a prime example of Roman architecture."
      },
      {
        question: "Which sea borders Croatia to the west?",
        options: [
          "Adriatic Sea",
          "Mediterranean Sea",
          "Aegean Sea",
          "Ionian Sea"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Adriatic Sea",
        explanation:
          "Croatia has a long coastline along the Adriatic Sea, known for its clear waters and beautiful islands."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the traditional Croatian dish made of grilled meat and served with side dishes?",
        options: ["Ćevapi", "Peka", "Sarma", "Fritaja"],
        correctAnswer: "Ćevapi",
        explanation:
          "Ćevapi are small, grilled minced meat sausages, often served with onions and bread."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which UNESCO World Heritage site in Croatia is famous for its ancient Roman amphitheater?",
        options: [
          "Pula Arena",
          "Diocletian's Palace",
          "Old Town of Dubrovnik",
          "Plitvice Lakes"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Pula Arena",
        explanation:
          "The Pula Arena is one of the best-preserved Roman amphitheaters in the world."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which Croatian island is known for its lavender fields and is a popular tourist destination?",
        options: ["Hvar", "Korčula", "Brač", "Vis"],
        correctAnswer: "Hvar",
        explanation:
          "Hvar is famous for its stunning landscapes, vibrant nightlife, and lavender fields."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the name of the Croatian traditional folk dance that is performed in circles?",
        options: ["Kolo", "Šokačko", "Lindo", "Mali"],
        correctAnswer: "Kolo",
        explanation:
          "Kolo is a traditional Croatian folk dance characterized by circular formations and lively music."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which Croatian city is known as the 'Pearl of the Adriatic'?",
        options: ["Zadar", "Dubrovnik", "Rijeka", "Pula"],
        correctAnswer: "Dubrovnik",
        explanation:
          "Dubrovnik is often referred to as the 'Pearl of the Adriatic' for its stunning medieval architecture and coastal views."
      }
    ]
  },
  France: {
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the capital of France?",
        options: ["Paris", "Marseille", "Lyon", "Nice"],
        correctAnswer: "Paris",
        explanation:
          "Paris is the capital and largest city of France, known for its art, fashion, and culture."
      },
      {
        question: "Which iconic landmark in Paris was completed in 1889?",
        options: [
          "Louvre Museum",
          "Eiffel Tower",
          "Notre-Dame Cathedral",
          "Arc de Triomphe"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Eiffel Tower",
        explanation:
          "The Eiffel Tower is an iconic symbol of France and one of the most recognizable structures in the world."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the traditional French pastry made of layers of puff pastry and cream filling?",
        options: ["Macaron", "Éclair", "Mille-feuille", "Tarte Tatin"],
        correctAnswer: "Mille-feuille",
        explanation:
          "Mille-feuille, also known as Napoleon, consists of layers of puff pastry and pastry cream."
      },
      {
        question: "Which river flows through the city of Paris?",
        options: ["Seine", "Loire", "Rhone", "Garonne"],
        correctAnswer: "Seine",
        explanation:
          "The Seine River runs through the heart of Paris and is famous for its beautiful bridges."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the currency used in France?",
        options: ["Franc", "Euro", "Dollar", "Pound"],
        correctAnswer: "Euro",
        explanation:
          "France adopted the Euro as its official currency in 2002, replacing the French Franc."
      },
      {
        question: "Which famous art museum in Paris is home to the Mona Lisa?",
        options: [
          "Musée d'Orsay",
          "Centre Pompidou",
          "Louvre Museum",
          "Musée de l'Orangerie"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Louvre Museum",
        explanation:
          "The Louvre Museum is one of the largest and most visited art museums in the world, housing the Mona Lisa."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the name of the famous French dish made of beef stewed in red wine?",
        options: [
          "Coq au Vin",
          "Boeuf Bourguignon",
          "Ratatouille",
          "Bouillabaisse"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Boeuf Bourguignon",
        explanation:
          "Boeuf Bourguignon is a traditional French dish that features beef slow-cooked in red wine with vegetables."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which region in France is famous for its vineyards and produces Champagne?",
        options: ["Bordeaux", "Provence", "Champagne", "Normandy"],
        correctAnswer: "Champagne",
        explanation:
          "The Champagne region is renowned for producing the sparkling wine known as Champagne."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the French term for the meal eaten in the evening?",
        options: ["Déjeuner", "Dîner", "Souper", "Petit déjeuner"],
        correctAnswer: "Dîner",
        explanation:
          "Dîner refers to the evening meal in France, often enjoyed later in the day."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the name of the annual French celebration held on July 14th?",
        options: [
          "Bastille Day",
          "Labor Day",
          "All Saints' Day",
          "Armistice Day"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Bastille Day",
        explanation:
          "Bastille Day commemorates the French Revolution and the storming of the Bastille prison in 1789."
      }
    ]
  },
  Switzerland: {
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the capital of Switzerland?",
        options: ["Zurich", "Geneva", "Bern", "Basel"],
        correctAnswer: "Bern",
        explanation:
          "Bern is the capital city of Switzerland and is known for its well-preserved medieval city center."
      },
      {
        question: "Which mountain range runs along the border of Switzerland?",
        options: ["Alps", "Himalayas", "Rockies", "Andes"],
        correctAnswer: "Alps",
        explanation:
          "The Swiss Alps are renowned for their stunning landscapes, skiing, and hiking opportunities."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the official currency used in Switzerland?",
        options: ["Euro", "Swiss Franc", "Dollar", "Pound"],
        correctAnswer: "Swiss Franc",
        explanation:
          "The official currency of Switzerland is the Swiss Franc (CHF)."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which Swiss city is known for hosting many international organizations, including the United Nations?",
        options: ["Zurich", "Geneva", "Lausanne", "Basel"],
        correctAnswer: "Geneva",
        explanation:
          "Geneva is home to numerous international organizations and is often considered a global diplomatic hub."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the name of the famous Swiss cheese known for its holes?",
        options: ["Emmental", "Gruyère", "Raclette", "Appenzeller"],
        correctAnswer: "Emmental",
        explanation:
          "Emmental cheese is known for its distinctive holes and is a popular Swiss cheese variety."
      },
      {
        question: "Which Swiss city is famous for its chocolate and watches?",
        options: ["Lucerne", "Bern", "Zurich", "Lausanne"],
        correctAnswer: "Zurich",
        explanation:
          "Zurich is known for its high-quality chocolate and luxury watchmaking industries."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the traditional Swiss dish made of potatoes, cheese, and flour, often served melted?",
        options: ["Fondue", "Rösti", "Raclette", "Zopf"],
        correctAnswer: "Fondue",
        explanation:
          "Fondue is a traditional Swiss dish where melted cheese is served in a communal pot, typically enjoyed with bread."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which Swiss lake is known for its beautiful scenery and is a popular tourist destination?",
        options: [
          "Lake Geneva",
          "Lake Lucerne",
          "Lake Zurich",
          "Lake Constance"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Lake Geneva",
        explanation:
          "Lake Geneva, located between Switzerland and France, is known for its stunning views and vineyards."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the Swiss tradition of 'yodeling'?",
        options: [
          "A type of dance",
          "A form of vocal singing",
          "A type of cheese",
          "A traditional dish"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "A form of vocal singing",
        explanation:
          "Yodeling is a form of singing that involves rapid changes in pitch and is a traditional Swiss vocal art."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which Swiss city is famous for its medieval architecture and the Zytglogge clock tower?",
        options: ["Zurich", "Bern", "Geneva", "Basel"],
        correctAnswer: "Bern",
        explanation:
          "Bern features a well-preserved medieval old town and the famous Zytglogge clock tower."
      }
    ]
  },
  Nordic_Mythology: {
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Who is the chief god in Norse mythology?",
        options: ["Thor", "Odin", "Loki", "Freyr"],
        correctAnswer: "Odin",
        explanation:
          "Odin is the chief god in Norse mythology, associated with wisdom, healing, and death."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the name of the tree that connects the nine worlds in Norse cosmology?",
        options: ["Yggdrasil", "Asgard", "Valhalla", "Midgard"],
        correctAnswer: "Yggdrasil",
        explanation:
          "Yggdrasil is the World Tree that connects all nine realms in Norse mythology."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which creature is known for its role in Ragnarök, the end of the world?",
        options: ["Fenrir", "Jörmungandr", "Sleipnir", "Níðhöggr"],
        correctAnswer: "Fenrir",
        explanation:
          "Fenrir is a giant wolf prophesied to kill Odin during Ragnarök."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the name of the hall where warriors who died in battle are taken?",
        options: ["Asgard", "Valhalla", "Hel", "Midgard"],
        correctAnswer: "Valhalla",
        explanation:
          "Valhalla is the hall of the slain, where warriors feast and prepare for Ragnarök."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which goddess is associated with love and beauty in Norse mythology?",
        options: ["Freyja", "Frigg", "Hel", "Skadi"],
        correctAnswer: "Freyja",
        explanation:
          "Freyja is the goddess of love, beauty, and fertility in Norse mythology."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of Thor's hammer?",
        options: ["Gungnir", "Mjölnir", "Gram", "Draupnir"],
        correctAnswer: "Mjölnir",
        explanation:
          "Mjölnir is Thor's hammer, known for its destructive power and ability to return to him after being thrown."
      },
      {
        question: "Who is the trickster god in Norse mythology?",
        options: ["Odin", "Thor", "Loki", "Baldr"],
        correctAnswer: "Loki",
        explanation:
          "Loki is a shape-shifting trickster god known for his cunning and mischief."
      },
      {
        question: "Which goddess rules over the underworld in Norse mythology?",
        options: ["Freyja", "Frigg", "Hel", "Skadi"],
        correctAnswer: "Hel",
        explanation:
          "Hel is the goddess of the underworld, ruling over the realm of the dead that bears her name."
      },
      {
        question: "What event is known as Ragnarök?",
        options: [
          "The creation of the world",
          "The end of the world",
          "The birth of Odin",
          "The rise of Valhalla"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "The end of the world",
        explanation:
          "Ragnarök is the prophesied series of events that leads to the end of the world and the death of many gods."
      },
      {
        question: "What animal is often associated with Odin?",
        options: ["Wolf", "Eagle", "Horse", "Raven"],
        correctAnswer: "Raven",
        explanation:
          "Odin is often associated with ravens, which are his companions and symbolize wisdom and knowledge."
      }
    ]
  },
  Greek_Mythology: {
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Who is considered the king of the Greek gods?",
        options: ["Zeus", "Hades", "Poseidon", "Apollo"],
        correctAnswer: "Zeus",
        explanation:
          "Zeus is the king of the gods in Greek mythology, known as the god of the sky and thunder."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the name of the winged horse that sprang from the blood of Medusa?",
        options: ["Chimera", "Pegasus", "Cerberus", "Griffin"],
        correctAnswer: "Pegasus",
        explanation:
          "Pegasus is the winged horse in Greek mythology that was born from the blood of the Gorgon Medusa."
      },
      {
        question: "Which goddess is known for her wisdom and warfare?",
        options: ["Aphrodite", "Artemis", "Athena", "Demeter"],
        correctAnswer: "Athena",
        explanation:
          "Athena is the goddess of wisdom, courage, and warfare in Greek mythology."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the underworld in Greek mythology?",
        options: ["Elysium", "Tartarus", "Hades", "Acheron"],
        correctAnswer: "Hades",
        explanation:
          "Hades is both the name of the god of the underworld and the underworld itself in Greek mythology."
      },
      {
        question: "Which hero completed twelve labors as punishment?",
        options: ["Achilles", "Hercules", "Theseus", "Odysseus"],
        correctAnswer: "Hercules",
        explanation:
          "Hercules is known for completing twelve arduous labors, a punishment assigned to him by King Eurystheus."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the Greek goddess of love and beauty?",
        options: ["Artemis", "Demeter", "Aphrodite", "Hera"],
        correctAnswer: "Aphrodite",
        explanation:
          "Aphrodite is the goddess of love, beauty, and desire in Greek mythology."
      },
      {
        question: "Which titan is known for holding up the sky?",
        options: ["Cronus", "Atlas", "Prometheus", "Epimetheus"],
        correctAnswer: "Atlas",
        explanation:
          "Atlas is a titan in Greek mythology who is condemned to hold up the sky for eternity."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the name of the hero who fought against the Trojans in the Trojan War?",
        options: ["Hector", "Achilles", "Agamemnon", "Odysseus"],
        correctAnswer: "Achilles",
        explanation:
          "Achilles is a central character in the Trojan War, known for his strength and near invincibility."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which creature has the body of a lion and the head of a human?",
        options: ["Sphinx", "Minotaur", "Hydra", "Cerberus"],
        correctAnswer: "Sphinx",
        explanation:
          "The Sphinx is a mythical creature with the body of a lion and the head of a human, known for posing riddles."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the name of the epic poem that recounts Odysseus's journey home after the Trojan War?",
        options: ["The Iliad", "The Odyssey", "The Aeneid", "The Argonautica"],
        correctAnswer: "The Odyssey",
        explanation:
          "The Odyssey is an epic poem attributed to Homer, detailing Odysseus's long journey home from Troy."
      }
    ]
  },
  Ancient_Egypt: {
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Who was the god of the sun in ancient Egyptian mythology?",
        options: ["Osiris", "Horus", "Ra", "Anubis"],
        correctAnswer: "Ra",
        explanation:
          "Ra is the ancient Egyptian sun god, often depicted with a falcon head and a solar disk."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the name of the ancient Egyptian writing system using pictorial symbols?",
        options: ["Cuneiform", "Hieroglyphics", "Sanskrit", "Phoenician"],
        correctAnswer: "Hieroglyphics",
        explanation:
          "Hieroglyphics is the writing system used in ancient Egypt, consisting of symbols representing sounds and concepts."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the name of the ancient Egyptian queen known for her beauty and political influence?",
        options: ["Nefertiti", "Cleopatra", "Hatshepsut", "Isis"],
        correctAnswer: "Cleopatra",
        explanation:
          "Cleopatra VII was the last active ruler of the Ptolemaic Kingdom of Egypt, known for her intelligence and beauty."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which ancient Egyptian monument is known as a tomb for pharaohs?",
        options: ["Sphinx", "Obelisk", "Pyramid", "Temple"],
        correctAnswer: "Pyramid",
        explanation:
          "The pyramids were monumental tombs built for pharaohs, most famously the Pyramids of Giza."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who was the ancient Egyptian god of the afterlife and the dead?",
        options: ["Osiris", "Set", "Horus", "Thoth"],
        correctAnswer: "Osiris",
        explanation:
          "Osiris is the god of the afterlife, resurrection, and agriculture in ancient Egyptian mythology."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What was the primary purpose of mummification in ancient Egypt?",
        options: [
          "Preservation for the afterlife",
          "Religious ritual",
          "Artistic expression",
          "Medical practice"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Preservation for the afterlife",
        explanation:
          "Mummification was practiced to preserve the body for the afterlife, reflecting the ancient Egyptians' beliefs about death."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What was the capital city of ancient Egypt during the New Kingdom?",
        options: ["Memphis", "Thebes", "Alexandria", "Cairo"],
        correctAnswer: "Thebes",
        explanation:
          "Thebes was the capital city of ancient Egypt during the New Kingdom and a major religious center."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which ancient Egyptian goddess is associated with motherhood and fertility?",
        options: ["Isis", "Hathor", "Bastet", "Sekhmet"],
        correctAnswer: "Isis",
        explanation:
          "Isis is the goddess of motherhood, fertility, and magic in ancient Egyptian mythology."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What was the significance of the Nile River in ancient Egypt?",
        options: ["Transportation", "Farming", "Religion", "All of the above"],
        correctAnswer: "All of the above",
        explanation:
          "The Nile River was crucial for transportation, agriculture, and religious practices in ancient Egypt."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which ancient Egyptian pharaoh is known for building the Great Pyramid?",
        options: ["Khufu", "Ramses II", "Tutankhamun", "Akhenaten"],
        correctAnswer: "Khufu",
        explanation:
          "Khufu, also known as Cheops, was the pharaoh who commissioned the Great Pyramid of Giza."
      }
    ]
  },
  USA: {
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What year did the United States declare its independence?",
        options: ["1776", "1783", "1791", "1801"],
        correctAnswer: "1776",
        explanation:
          "The United States declared its independence from Britain on July 4, 1776."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which document serves as the supreme law of the United States?",
        options: [
          "The Declaration of Independence",
          "The Bill of Rights",
          "The Constitution",
          "The Emancipation Proclamation"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "The Constitution",
        explanation:
          "The Constitution is the supreme law of the United States, outlining the framework of the government."
      },
      {
        question: "Who was the first President of the United States?",
        options: [
          "Thomas Jefferson",
          "George Washington",
          "Abraham Lincoln",
          "John Adams"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "George Washington",
        explanation:
          "George Washington was inaugurated as the first President of the United States in 1789."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the capital city of the United States?",
        options: ["New York", "Washington, D.C.", "Los Angeles", "Chicago"],
        correctAnswer: "Washington, D.C.",
        explanation:
          "Washington, D.C. is the capital city of the United States and the seat of the federal government."
      },
      {
        question: "Which war was fought to end slavery in the United States?",
        options: [
          "The Revolutionary War",
          "The Civil War",
          "World War I",
          "World War II"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "The Civil War",
        explanation:
          "The Civil War, fought from 1861 to 1865, was primarily about ending slavery in the United States."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the national anthem of the United States?",
        options: [
          "America the Beautiful",
          "The Star-Spangled Banner",
          "God Bless America",
          "This Land Is Your Land"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "The Star-Spangled Banner",
        explanation:
          "The Star-Spangled Banner is the national anthem of the United States, written by Francis Scott Key."
      },
      {
        question: "Which amendment abolished slavery in the United States?",
        options: [
          "13th Amendment",
          "14th Amendment",
          "15th Amendment",
          "19th Amendment"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "13th Amendment",
        explanation:
          "The 13th Amendment, ratified in 1865, abolished slavery in the United States."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who was the leader of the civil rights movement in the 1960s?",
        options: [
          "Malcolm X",
          "Martin Luther King Jr.",
          "Rosa Parks",
          "Frederick Douglass"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Martin Luther King Jr.",
        explanation:
          "Martin Luther King Jr. was a prominent leader in the civil rights movement, advocating for nonviolent protest."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the largest state in the United States by area?",
        options: ["Texas", "California", "Alaska", "Florida"],
        correctAnswer: "Alaska",
        explanation:
          "Alaska is the largest state in the United States by area, significantly larger than any other state."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which landmark is known as a symbol of freedom in the United States?",
        options: [
          "The Washington Monument",
          "The Golden Gate Bridge",
          "The Statue of Liberty",
          "Mount Rushmore"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "The Statue of Liberty",
        explanation:
          "The Statue of Liberty is a symbol of freedom and democracy, located on Liberty Island in New York Harbor."
      }
    ]
  },
  Canada: {
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the capital city of Canada?",
        options: ["Toronto", "Vancouver", "Ottawa", "Montreal"],
        correctAnswer: "Ottawa",
        explanation:
          "Ottawa is the capital city of Canada, located in the province of Ontario."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the national anthem of Canada?",
        options: [
          "O Canada",
          "The Maple Leaf Forever",
          "God Save the Queen",
          "This Land Is Your Land"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "O Canada",
        explanation:
          "O Canada is the national anthem of Canada, officially adopted in 1980."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the official language of Canada?",
        options: ["English", "French", "Both English and French", "Spanish"],
        correctAnswer: "Both English and French",
        explanation:
          "Canada is officially bilingual, recognizing both English and French as official languages."
      },
      {
        question: "What animal is a national symbol of Canada?",
        options: ["Beaver", "Eagle", "Moose", "Bear"],
        correctAnswer: "Beaver",
        explanation:
          "The beaver is a national symbol of Canada, known for its role in the fur trade."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the Canadian constitution?",
        options: [
          "The Constitution Act",
          "The British North America Act",
          "The Charter of Rights and Freedoms",
          "The Statute of Westminster"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "The Constitution Act",
        explanation:
          "The Constitution Act, 1867, serves as the foundation of Canada's constitutional framework."
      },
      {
        question: "Which province is known for its French-speaking population?",
        options: ["British Columbia", "Alberta", "Quebec", "Nova Scotia"],
        correctAnswer: "Quebec",
        explanation:
          "Quebec is the only province in Canada where French is the official language and widely spoken."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the largest city in Canada by population?",
        options: ["Toronto", "Montreal", "Vancouver", "Calgary"],
        correctAnswer: "Toronto",
        explanation:
          "Toronto is the largest city in Canada by population, located in Ontario."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the currency used in Canada?",
        options: ["Canadian Dollar", "US Dollar", "Euro", "British Pound"],
        correctAnswer: "Canadian Dollar",
        explanation:
          "The currency used in Canada is the Canadian Dollar, often abbreviated as CAD."
      },
      {
        question: "Which famous natural landmark is located in Canada?",
        options: [
          "Grand Canyon",
          "Niagara Falls",
          "Mount Rushmore",
          "Yellowstone National Park"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Niagara Falls",
        explanation:
          "Niagara Falls, located on the border between Canada and the United States, is a famous natural landmark."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which historical document established Canada as a self-governing dominion?",
        options: [
          "The BNA Act",
          "The Constitution Act",
          "The Statute of Westminster",
          "The Quebec Act"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "The BNA Act",
        explanation:
          "The British North America Act (BNA Act) of 1867 established Canada as a self-governing dominion."
      }
    ]
  },
  Australia: {
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the capital city of Australia?",
        options: ["Sydney", "Melbourne", "Canberra", "Brisbane"],
        correctAnswer: "Canberra",
        explanation:
          "Canberra is the capital city of Australia, chosen as a compromise between Sydney and Melbourne."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the national animal of Australia?",
        options: ["Kangaroo", "Koala", "Emu", "Dingo"],
        correctAnswer: "Kangaroo",
        explanation:
          "The kangaroo is a national symbol of Australia and is unique to the country."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the official language of Australia?",
        options: ["English", "French", "German", "Dutch"],
        correctAnswer: "English",
        explanation:
          "English is the official language of Australia, spoken by the majority of the population."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the famous rock formation in Australia?",
        options: [
          "Uluru",
          "The Great Barrier Reef",
          "The Sydney Opera House",
          "The Twelve Apostles"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Uluru",
        explanation:
          "Uluru, also known as Ayers Rock, is a sacred site for Indigenous Australians and a popular tourist destination."
      },
      {
        question: "Which country is located to the north of Australia?",
        options: ["New Zealand", "Papua New Guinea", "Indonesia", "Fiji"],
        correctAnswer: "Papua New Guinea",
        explanation:
          "Papua New Guinea is located to the north of Australia, separated by the Torres Strait."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the largest city in Australia by population?",
        options: ["Sydney", "Melbourne", "Brisbane", "Perth"],
        correctAnswer: "Sydney",
        explanation:
          "Sydney is the largest city in Australia by population and is known for its iconic harbor and Opera House."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the currency used in Australia?",
        options: ["Australian Dollar", "US Dollar", "Euro", "Pound Sterling"],
        correctAnswer: "Australian Dollar",
        explanation:
          "The currency used in Australia is the Australian Dollar, often abbreviated as AUD."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which marine ecosystem is the largest in the world and is located off the coast of Australia?",
        options: [
          "The Great Barrier Reef",
          "The Coral Triangle",
          "The Red Sea",
          "The Mediterranean Sea"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "The Great Barrier Reef",
        explanation:
          "The Great Barrier Reef is the largest coral reef system in the world, located off the coast of Queensland, Australia."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which Australian city is known for its cultural events and festivals?",
        options: ["Brisbane", "Melbourne", "Sydney", "Perth"],
        correctAnswer: "Melbourne",
        explanation:
          "Melbourne is known for its vibrant arts scene and hosts numerous cultural events and festivals throughout the year."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the indigenous people of Australia?",
        options: [
          "Maori",
          "Aboriginal",
          "Torres Strait Islanders",
          "Both Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islanders"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Both Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islanders",
        explanation:
          "The indigenous people of Australia are known as Aboriginal Australians and Torres Strait Islanders."
      }
    ]
  },
  UK: {
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the capital city of the United Kingdom?",
        options: ["London", "Edinburgh", "Cardiff", "Belfast"],
        correctAnswer: "London",
        explanation:
          "London is the capital city of the United Kingdom and is known for its rich history and cultural diversity."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which document established the constitutional monarchy in the UK?",
        options: [
          "The Magna Carta",
          "The Bill of Rights",
          "The Act of Union",
          "The Glorious Revolution"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "The Bill of Rights",
        explanation:
          "The Bill of Rights, enacted in 1689, established the constitutional monarchy and limited the powers of the king."
      },
      {
        question: "Who is the current monarch of the United Kingdom?",
        options: [
          "Queen Elizabeth II",
          "King Charles III",
          "Prince William",
          "Prince Harry"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "King Charles III",
        explanation:
          "King Charles III is the current monarch of the United Kingdom, having ascended to the throne in 2022."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the national flower of England?",
        options: ["Rose", "Thistle", "Daffodil", "Shamrock"],
        correctAnswer: "Rose",
        explanation:
          "The rose is the national flower of England and symbolizes the country."
      },
      {
        question: "Which famous landmark is known as a symbol of London?",
        options: [
          "Big Ben",
          "The Tower of London",
          "The London Eye",
          "The Shard"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Big Ben",
        explanation:
          "Big Ben is the nickname for the Great Bell of the clock at the north end of the Palace of Westminster in London."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the currency used in the United Kingdom?",
        options: ["Pound Sterling", "Euro", "Dollar", "Yen"],
        correctAnswer: "Pound Sterling",
        explanation:
          "The currency used in the United Kingdom is the Pound Sterling, often symbolized as £."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the longest river in the UK?",
        options: [
          "River Thames",
          "River Severn",
          "River Trent",
          "River Mersey"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "River Severn",
        explanation:
          "The River Severn is the longest river in the UK, flowing through Wales and England."
      },
      {
        question: "Which event marked the beginning of the English Civil War?",
        options: [
          "The Glorious Revolution",
          "The Execution of Charles I",
          "The Long Parliament",
          "The Petition of Right"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "The Long Parliament",
        explanation:
          "The Long Parliament convened in 1640 and its disputes with King Charles I led to the English Civil War."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the official residence of the Prime Minister of the UK?",
        options: [
          "Buckingham Palace",
          "10 Downing Street",
          "The Houses of Parliament",
          "The Tower of London"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "10 Downing Street",
        explanation:
          "10 Downing Street is the official residence and office of the Prime Minister of the United Kingdom."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the largest city in Scotland?",
        options: ["Edinburgh", "Glasgow", "Aberdeen", "Dundee"],
        correctAnswer: "Glasgow",
        explanation:
          "Glasgow is the largest city in Scotland and known for its vibrant cultural scene."
      }
    ]
  },
  Ireland: {
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the capital city of Ireland?",
        options: ["Dublin", "Cork", "Galway", "Limerick"],
        correctAnswer: "Dublin",
        explanation:
          "Dublin is the capital city of Ireland and is known for its historical and cultural significance."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the national symbol of Ireland?",
        options: [
          "The Harp",
          "The Shamrock",
          "The Celtic Cross",
          "The Triskelion"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "The Harp",
        explanation:
          "The harp is a national symbol of Ireland and is associated with Irish culture and history."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the currency used in Ireland?",
        options: ["Euro", "Pound Sterling", "Dollar", "Franc"],
        correctAnswer: "Euro",
        explanation:
          "The currency used in Ireland is the Euro, which was adopted in 2002."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the official language of Ireland?",
        options: ["English", "Irish", "Both English and Irish", "French"],
        correctAnswer: "Both English and Irish",
        explanation:
          "Ireland recognizes both English and Irish as official languages, with Irish being the first official language."
      },
      {
        question: "What famous festival celebrates Irish culture and heritage?",
        options: [
          "Oktoberfest",
          "St. Patrick's Day",
          "Bastille Day",
          "Burns Night"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "St. Patrick's Day",
        explanation:
          "St. Patrick's Day, celebrated on March 17th, honors St. Patrick, the patron saint of Ireland."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the name of the ancient monument in Ireland known for its large stone structures?",
        options: [
          "Stonehenge",
          "Newgrange",
          "Giant's Causeway",
          "The Ring of Kerry"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Newgrange",
        explanation:
          "Newgrange is a prehistoric monument in Ireland, older than Stonehenge, and is famous for its winter solstice alignment."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which Irish city is known for its medieval history and vibrant nightlife?",
        options: ["Dublin", "Belfast", "Galway", "Cork"],
        correctAnswer: "Dublin",
        explanation:
          "Dublin is known for its rich medieval history and vibrant nightlife, with numerous pubs and cultural events."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the famous Irish folk dance?",
        options: ["Samba", "Ballet", "Irish Dance", "Flamenco"],
        correctAnswer: "Irish Dance",
        explanation:
          "Irish Dance is a traditional form of dance that is characterized by rapid leg and foot movements while the upper body remains stationary."
      },
      {
        question: "Which famous literary figure is associated with Ireland?",
        options: [
          "William Shakespeare",
          "James Joyce",
          "Charles Dickens",
          "Mark Twain"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "James Joyce",
        explanation:
          "James Joyce is a renowned Irish novelist known for works like 'Ulysses' and 'A Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man.'"
      },
      {
        question: "What natural feature is known as the 'Emerald Isle'?",
        options: [
          "The Cliffs of Moher",
          "The Ring of Kerry",
          "Ireland",
          "The Giant's Causeway"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Ireland",
        explanation:
          "Ireland is often referred to as the 'Emerald Isle' due to its lush green landscape."
      }
    ]
  },
  Netherlands: {
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the capital city of the Netherlands?",
        options: ["Amsterdam", "Rotterdam", "The Hague", "Utrecht"],
        correctAnswer: "Amsterdam",
        explanation:
          "Amsterdam is the capital city of the Netherlands, known for its canals, museums, and vibrant culture."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the official language of the Netherlands?",
        options: ["Dutch", "German", "French", "English"],
        correctAnswer: "Dutch",
        explanation:
          "Dutch is the official language of the Netherlands and is spoken by the majority of the population."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What famous painting technique is associated with Dutch artist Vincent van Gogh?",
        options: [
          "Cubism",
          "Impressionism",
          "Surrealism",
          "Post-Impressionism"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Post-Impressionism",
        explanation:
          "Vincent van Gogh is known for his Post-Impressionist works, characterized by bold colors and expressive brushwork."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the currency used in the Netherlands?",
        options: ["Euro", "Dutch Guilder", "Pound Sterling", "Franc"],
        correctAnswer: "Euro",
        explanation:
          "The currency used in the Netherlands is the Euro, adopted in 2002."
      },
      {
        question: "Which famous windmill is a symbol of the Netherlands?",
        options: [
          "De Zaanse Schans",
          "Kinderdijk",
          "Kinderdijk Windmill",
          "Haarlem"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Kinderdijk",
        explanation:
          "Kinderdijk is famous for its historic windmills and is a UNESCO World Heritage site."
      },
      {
        question: "What flower is the Netherlands famous for?",
        options: ["Rose", "Tulip", "Daisy", "Lily"],
        correctAnswer: "Tulip",
        explanation:
          "The Netherlands is famous for its tulips, particularly during the spring flower season."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the name of the large dam that protects the Netherlands from flooding?",
        options: ["Afsluitdijk", "Zuiderzee Works", "Euromast", "Delta Works"],
        correctAnswer: "Afsluitdijk",
        explanation:
          "The Afsluitdijk is a major dam that protects the Netherlands from the North Sea and prevents flooding."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the name of the annual event in the Netherlands that celebrates the arrival of spring with flower parades?",
        options: [
          "Tulip Festival",
          "Flower Parade",
          "King's Day",
          "Sinterklaas"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Flower Parade",
        explanation:
          "The Flower Parade (Bloemencorso) is an annual event that celebrates spring with stunning flower floats."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which Dutch city is known for its canals and historic architecture?",
        options: ["Amsterdam", "Rotterdam", "Utrecht", "Groningen"],
        correctAnswer: "Amsterdam",
        explanation:
          "Amsterdam is famous for its canals and historic architecture, attracting tourists from around the world."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the name of the national museum dedicated to Dutch art and history?",
        options: [
          "Rijksmuseum",
          "Van Gogh Museum",
          "Hermitage Amsterdam",
          "Stedelijk Museum"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Rijksmuseum",
        explanation:
          "The Rijksmuseum is the national museum dedicated to Dutch art and history, featuring works by Rembrandt and Vermeer."
      }
    ]
  },
  Austria: {
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the capital city of Austria?",
        options: ["Vienna", "Salzburg", "Innsbruck", "Graz"],
        correctAnswer: "Vienna",
        explanation:
          "Vienna is the capital city of Austria, known for its historic architecture and cultural heritage."
      },
      {
        question: "Which famous composer was born in Austria?",
        options: [
          "Ludwig van Beethoven",
          "Johann Sebastian Bach",
          "Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart",
          "Franz Schubert"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart",
        explanation:
          "Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart, one of the most influential composers of the classical era, was born in Salzburg, Austria."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the currency used in Austria?",
        options: ["Euro", "Austrian Schilling", "Swiss Franc", "Dollar"],
        correctAnswer: "Euro",
        explanation:
          "Austria adopted the Euro as its official currency in 2002, replacing the Austrian Schilling."
      },
      {
        question: "Which mountain range runs along the border of Austria?",
        options: ["Alps", "Carpathians", "Apennines", "Pyrenees"],
        correctAnswer: "Alps",
        explanation:
          "The Alps are a major mountain range that runs along the southern border of Austria, known for their stunning landscapes."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the famous palace located in Vienna?",
        options: [
          "Schönbrunn Palace",
          "Neuschwanstein Castle",
          "Palace of Versailles",
          "Buckingham Palace"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Schönbrunn Palace",
        explanation:
          "Schönbrunn Palace is a UNESCO World Heritage site and was the summer residence of the Habsburgs."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the national dish of Austria?",
        options: ["Schnitzel", "Goulash", "Strudel", "Bratwurst"],
        correctAnswer: "Schnitzel",
        explanation:
          "Wiener Schnitzel, a breaded and fried veal cutlet, is considered the national dish of Austria."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which famous festival is celebrated in Vienna with balls and music?",
        options: [
          "Oktoberfest",
          "Vienna Opera Ball",
          "Carnival",
          "Bastille Day"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Vienna Opera Ball",
        explanation:
          "The Vienna Opera Ball is an annual event that showcases classical music and ballroom dancing in Vienna."
      },
      {
        question: "What river flows through Vienna?",
        options: ["Danube", "Rhine", "Elbe", "Seine"],
        correctAnswer: "Danube",
        explanation:
          "The Danube River flows through Vienna and is one of the longest rivers in Europe."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the famous Christmas market in Vienna?",
        options: [
          "Christkindlmarkt",
          "Oberndorf Market",
          "Salzburg Christmas Market",
          "Nuremberg Christkindlesmarkt"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Christkindlmarkt",
        explanation:
          "The Christkindlmarkt in Vienna is one of the oldest and most famous Christmas markets in Europe."
      },
      {
        question: "What is Austria's national sport?",
        options: ["Football", "Ice Hockey", "Skiing", "Tennis"],
        correctAnswer: "Skiing",
        explanation:
          "Skiing is a popular national sport in Austria, known for its excellent ski resorts in the Alps."
      }
    ]
  },
  Czech_Republic: {
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the capital city of the Czech Republic?",
        options: ["Prague", "Brno", "Plzeň", "Ostrava"],
        correctAnswer: "Prague",
        explanation:
          "Prague is the capital city of the Czech Republic, renowned for its historic architecture and cultural heritage."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the currency used in the Czech Republic?",
        options: ["Czech Koruna", "Euro", "Czech Crown", "Dollar"],
        correctAnswer: "Czech Koruna",
        explanation:
          "The currency used in the Czech Republic is the Czech Koruna (CZK), which is not the Euro."
      },
      {
        question: "Which famous landmark is known as the Charles Bridge?",
        options: [
          "Prague Castle",
          "Old Town Square",
          "Charles Bridge",
          "Astronomical Clock"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Charles Bridge",
        explanation:
          "Charles Bridge is a historic bridge in Prague that connects the Old Town with the Lesser Town and features stunning sculptures."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the national drink of the Czech Republic?",
        options: ["Beer", "Wine", "Vodka", "Whiskey"],
        correctAnswer: "Beer",
        explanation:
          "The Czech Republic is famous for its beer, with a long tradition of brewing, particularly pilsner lager."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the famous castle located in Prague?",
        options: [
          "Prague Castle",
          "Karlštejn Castle",
          "Český Krumlov Castle",
          "Hluboká Castle"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Prague Castle",
        explanation:
          "Prague Castle is one of the largest ancient castles in the world and a UNESCO World Heritage site."
      },
      {
        question: "Which famous composer was from the Czech Republic?",
        options: [
          "Ludwig van Beethoven",
          "Antonín Dvořák",
          "Johann Sebastian Bach",
          "Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Antonín Dvořák",
        explanation:
          "Antonín Dvořák was a famous composer from the Czech Republic, known for his symphonies and chamber music."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the name of the famous puppet show tradition in the Czech Republic?",
        options: ["Marionette", "Shadow Play", "Pantomime", "Kabuki"],
        correctAnswer: "Marionette",
        explanation:
          "The Czech Republic is known for its rich tradition of marionette puppetry, particularly in Prague."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the largest city in the Czech Republic after Prague?",
        options: ["Brno", "Plzeň", "Ostrava", "Liberec"],
        correctAnswer: "Brno",
        explanation:
          "Brno is the second largest city in the Czech Republic and is known for its university and modern architecture."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the famous festival celebrating Czech culture and traditions?",
        options: [
          "Oktoberfest",
          "Midsummer Festival",
          "Prague Spring Festival",
          "Christmas Market"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Prague Spring Festival",
        explanation:
          "The Prague Spring Festival is an annual event celebrating classical music, particularly orchestral and opera performances."
      },
      {
        question: "Which river flows through Prague?",
        options: ["Elbe", "Vltava", "Danube", "Oder"],
        correctAnswer: "Vltava",
        explanation:
          "The Vltava River flows through Prague and is the longest river in the Czech Republic."
      }
    ]
  },
  Hungary: {
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the capital city of Hungary?",
        options: ["Budapest", "Debrecen", "Szeged", "Miskolc"],
        correctAnswer: "Budapest",
        explanation:
          "Budapest is the capital city of Hungary, known for its stunning architecture and thermal baths."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the currency used in Hungary?",
        options: ["Forint", "Euro", "Crown", "Dollar"],
        correctAnswer: "Forint",
        explanation:
          "The currency used in Hungary is the Forint (HUF), which is not the Euro."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the famous thermal bath in Budapest?",
        options: [
          "Gellért Baths",
          "Rudas Baths",
          "Széchenyi Baths",
          "All of the above"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "All of the above",
        explanation:
          "Budapest is famous for its thermal baths, including Gellért, Rudas, and Széchenyi Baths."
      },
      {
        question: "Which river flows through Budapest?",
        options: ["Danube", "Tisza", "Sava", "Elbe"],
        correctAnswer: "Danube",
        explanation:
          "The Danube River flows through Budapest, separating the city into Buda and Pest."
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the traditional Hungarian dish made of stewed meat and vegetables?",
        options: ["Goulash", "Sauerbraten", "Ratatouille", "Borscht"],
        correctAnswer: "Goulash",
        explanation:
          "Goulash is a traditional Hungarian dish made of meat, vegetables, and paprika, often served as a stew."
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which famous Hungarian composer is known for his Hungarian Rhapsodies?",
        options: [
          "Franz Liszt",
          "Johann Strauss",
          "Zoltán Kodály",
          "Béla Bartók"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Franz Liszt",
        explanation:
          "Franz Liszt was a renowned Hungarian composer and pianist known for his virtuosic compositions, including the Hungarian Rhapsodies."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the famous castle located in Budapest?",
        options: [
          "Buda Castle",
          "Vajdahunyad Castle",
          "Fisherman's Bastion",
          "Gellért Hill"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Buda Castle",
        explanation:
          "Buda Castle is a historic castle complex located on Castle Hill in Budapest, offering stunning views of the city."
      },
      {
        question: "Which festival celebrates the harvest in Hungary?",
        options: [
          "Oktoberfest",
          "Wine Festival",
          "Harvest Festival",
          "Folk Festival"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Harvest Festival",
        explanation:
          "The Harvest Festival in Hungary celebrates the end of the harvest season with various cultural events and local products."
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the famous Hungarian folk dance?",
        options: ["Csárdás", "Tango", "Waltz", "Samba"],
        correctAnswer: "Csárdás",
        explanation:
          "Csárdás is a traditional Hungarian folk dance characterized by its fast and slow tempos."
      },
      {
        question: "Which UNESCO World Heritage site is located in Hungary?",
        options: [
          "The Great Market Hall",
          "Hortobágy National Park",
          "Buda Castle",
          "All of the above"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "All of the above",
        explanation:
          "Hungary has several UNESCO World Heritage sites, including Buda Castle and Hortobágy National Park."
      }
    ]
  }
};
